
[
    {
      "question": "Ho Chi Minh formed the Vietminh to fight Japan and.....",
      "optionA": "United States",
      "optionB": "France",
      "optionC": "England",
      "optionD": "Indonesia",
      "answer": "France"
    },
    {
      "question": "President Harry Truman sign legislation granting....million dollars in military aid to the French for the war in Indochina",
      "optionA": "5",
      "optionB": "12",
      "optionC": "15",
      "optionD": "20",
      "answer": "15"
    },
    {
      "question": "The battle of Dien Bien Phu began in",
      "optionA": "1945",
      "optionB": "1950",
      "optionC": "1952",
      "optionD": "1954",
      "answer": "1954"
    },
    {
      "question": "The Soviet Union proposed that North Vietnam and.... be admitted to the United Nations as seperate states.",
      "optionA": "United States",
      "optionB": "South Vietnam",
      "optionC": "China",
      "optionD": "Japan",
      "answer": "South Vietnam"
    },
    {
      "question": "President Kennedy criticized..... in a television interview.",
      "optionA": "Ho Chi Minh",
      "optionB": "Diem",
      "optionC": "Sherlock Holmes",
      "optionD": "Ngo Dinh Nhu",
      "answer": "Diem"
    },
    {
      "question": "The first known kingdom to exist in what is now North Vietnam was called what?",
      "optionA": "Van Lang",
      "optionB": "Cam Lo",
      "optionC": "Bach Viet",
      "optionD": "Ca Lu",
      "answer": "Van Lang"
    },
    {
      "question": "In 258 BC two states, Tay Au and Lac Viet, merged to form what new kingdom in the north?",
      "optionA": "Au Lac",
      "optionB": "Lac Tay",
      "optionC": "Tay Viet",
      "optionD": "Viet Au",
      "answer": "Au Lac"
    },
    {
      "question": "The United States official entered the Vietnam War when they.....",
      "optionA": "Signed a treaty with France",
      "optionB": "Congress passed the Gulf of Tonkin resolution",
      "optionC": "Bombed North Vietnam",
      "optionD": "Arrested Ho Chi Minh",
      "answer": "Bombed North Vietnam"
    },
    {
      "question": "The Tet Offensive began in .....",
      "optionA": "1945",
      "optionB": "1950",
      "optionC": "1965",
      "optionD": "1968",
      "answer": "1968"
    },
    {
      "question": "American Troops leave Vietnam in",
      "optionA": "1965",
      "optionB": "1973",
      "optionC": "1978",
      "optionD": "1982",
      "answer": "1973"
    },
    {
      "question": "What was the Chinese name for Vietnam during its 1,000 year rule?",
      "optionA": "Tonkin",
      "optionB": "Annam",
      "optionC": "Nanyue",
      "optionD": "Cochin",
      "answer": "Nanyue"
    },
    {
      "question": "Where is the Vietnam Veteran's Memorial located?",
      "optionA": "Cleveland, Ohio",
      "optionB": "Seattle, WA",
      "optionC": "Atlanta, Ga",
      "optionD": "Washington, D.C",
      "answer": "Washington, D.C"
    },
    {
      "question": "While all of these changes were taking place in North Vietnam, another state was developing in what is now central-south Vietnam. What was this proto-state called?",
      "optionA": "Lam Ap",
      "optionB": "Nang Huy",
      "optionC": "Dac Biet",
      "optionD": "Lac Duy",
      "answer": "Lam Ap"
    },
    {
      "question": "More than 1,000 years of Chinese rule in Vietnam was initiated in 111 BC when troops were dispatched to take control of the Vietnamese homeland. During which Chinese dynasty did this take place?",
      "optionA": "Song",
      "optionB": "Zhou",
      "optionC": "Han",
      "optionD": "Wu",
      "answer": "Han"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who was the first emperor of independent Vietnam?",
      "optionA": "Hong Diep",
      "optionB": "Thi Ngoc",
      "optionC": "Vu Xinh",
      "optionD": "Ngo Quyen",
      "answer": "Ngo Quyen"
    }
  ]